Finding Aid for Inventors Council of Michigan records, 1983-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Inventors Council of Michigan records 1983-1990
Inventors Council of Michigan.
1 linear foot
9445 Bt 2
The Inventors Council of Michigan, chaired by J. Downs Herold, was founded in 1983 to provide assistance and support to Michigan inventors. Originally a not-for-profit organization, it was operated by the Industrial Development Division of the Institute of Science and Technology of the University of Michigan. Meeting minutes, newsletters and correspondence with inventors primarily documenting the organization's early years as a nonprofit organization.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received though J. Downs Herold of the University of Michigan Institute of Science and Technology (donor no. 5993 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Inventors Council of Michigan (INCOM) was founded in 1983 as "a council for individuals dedicated to assisting each other in the many steps of the invention and innovation process" ("Fact Sheet," F: Bylaws and Organization). INCOM was a not-for-profit organization operated by the Industrial Development Division of the Institute of Science and Technology of the University of Michigan under the direction and chairmanship of J. Downs Herold. It held monthly meetings for its over three-hundred members and provided such services to its inventor members as invention evaluations, consultation and discussions on marketing and manufacturing an invention, and creating networks between inventors and Michigan businesses. In 1988, the Industrial Development Division decided to transfer direction and support from the public to the private sector thus expanding its inventor-focused membership to include product developers and other groups concerned with economic development in Michigan.
The records of INCOM document the activities of INCOM and its services during its initial years as a nonprofit organization. The records include such types of materials as meeting minutes, newsletters, and correspondence with inventors. The folder "Transition to Private Sector" documents INCOM's decision to move from the public to the private sector in 1988.
Subjects:
Herold, J. Downs.; Inventors--Michigan.; Inventors Council of Michigan.
- Organizational records, 1983-1990
  - Board of Directors Meetings, 1983-1990, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Bylaws and Organization, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1984, 1987, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - General, 1983-1988, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters from Inventors, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
  - Financial Statements, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Funding, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - General Meetings, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Idea Car, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Innovation Evaluation Program, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Inventor of the Year Award, 1984-1988 (Box 1)
  - Manuals and Bibliographies for Inventors, undated (Box 1)
  - Membership, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1983-1988 (incomplete run) (Box 1)
  - Other INCOM Chapters and Michigan Inventors' Organizations, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Programs, Workshops, and Seminars, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Seed Capital Fund Proposal, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Small Business Development Center, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Transition to Private Sector, 1988 (Box 1)